Erases the border between art and activism.
The Thin Blue Line is a crime, documentary film directed by Errol Morris.
This unique documentary dramatically re-enacts the crime scene and
investigation of a police officer's murder in Dallas.
Self, played by Randall Adams.
Self, played by David Harris.
Self - Homicide Detective in Dallas, played by Gus Rose.
Self - Homicide Detective in Dallas, played by Jackie Johnson.
Self - Homicide Detective in Dallas, played by Marshall Touchton.
Self - Internal Affairs Investigator in Dallas, played by Dale Holt.
The Thin Blue Line is a 1988 American documentary film by Errol Morris, about the trial and
conviction of Randall Dale Adams for the 1976 shooting of Dallas police officer Robert W.
Morris became interested in the case while doing research for a film about Dr.
James Grigson, a psychiatrist known in Texas as "Dr.
Death" for testifying with "100 percent certainty" of a defendant's
recidivism in many trials, including that of Randall Adams.
The film centers around the "inconsistencies, incongruities and loose ends" of the case, and Morris, through his investigation, not only comes to a
different conclusion, but actually obtains an admission of Adams's innocence from the original suspect of the case, David Harris.
The "thin blue line" in the title "refers to what Mr.
Morris feels is an ironic, mythical image of a protective
policeman on the other side of anarchy".
The film won many awards, but was a controversial film among documentary film critics,
who felt the use of reenactment had no place in the documentary format.
For this reason, the film was not nominated for an Academy Award,
though it won several other awards for best documentary.
Roger Ebert "attributed its rejection to the inability of academy voters to appreciate innovative film making."
In 2001, the film was selected by the Library
of Congress for preservation in the United States National Film Registry as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of death penalty, texas,
investigation, dallas, texas, trial.